♪～
～♪
The Jinchuriki's Tears
（砂すなの里さとの忍）あっ ここにも
起爆札が残ってるぞ
There's a Paper Bomb left here, too!
（砂の里の忍）剥がした瞬間に
爆発するタイプだ
It's a type that explodes
the instant it's peeled off...
爆破処理するしかないな
We'll just have to detonate it.
I see.
そうか
（砂の里の忍）起爆札を爆発させる
We're detonating a Paper Bomb!
作業を中断して退避しろ
Stop working and take cover!
Let's do this.
（砂の里の忍）やるぞ
（砂の里の忍）うん
（砂の里の上役）今は
新たな風影かぜかげ候補のことなど
Now isn't the time to be discussing
candidates for a new Kazekage!
話してる場合ではない
（上役）しかし
万が一のことを考えて
But if you think about
the worst-case scenario,
先手を打っておくことも
重要では ないのか？
isn't it important to seize
the initiative?
（上役）それよりも風影様
奪還の方策を優先すべきだ
More importantly,
the plan to rescue Lord Kazekage
should be the priority!
（上役）重要なのは里の安全確保だ
Securing village safety
is what's important!
この状況で限られた戦力を
割くわけには いかぬ
We must not break up
our limited forces in conditions like this.
（上役）なんだと！
What did you say?!
Oh, excuse me...
（砂の里の忍）ああ すいません
Reporting!
報告します
An enemy trap has been discovered
in the rubble blocking the entrance.
（砂の里の忍）入り口を塞いでいる
ガレキの中に敵のトラップを発見
We are currently proceeding
with its detonation...
現在 爆破処理を進めていますが
ケガ人は なし
There have been no casualties.
However, a portion
of the entrance collapsed
ただし 爆発の影響で
入り口の一部が崩壊
due to the effects of the explosion.
It seems it will take
an extra half day for repairs!
復旧の見通しが さらに半日ほど
遅れそうだとのことです
（バキ）分かった
Got it. Arrange it so that those
who are available are dispatched
手の空いた者を すぐに
復旧現場に回すよう手配しろ
to the repair site immediately.
Yes, sir!
（砂の里の忍）はっ
（バキ）ん…
Hey wait!
Thanks to Gaara,
（バキ）我愛羅(があら)のおかげで
砂隠(すながく)れの里(さと) 自体は
the Village Hidden in the Sand was
left almost completely undamaged...
ほとんど無傷で済んだ
But...we paid too great
a price for that...
だが その代償として失ったものは
あまりにも大きい
（砂の里の忍）報告します
Reporting!
All of the bodies of those guarding
the skies have been verified.
上空の見張りをしていた者
全員の死体が確認されました
敵は空から里の中心部に
侵入したと考えて間違いないかと…
There is probably little doubt
that the enemy infiltrated
the center of the village from the sky...
Excuse me!
（砂の里の忍）失礼します
（バキ）なんだ
What?!
追跡部隊より連絡が入りました
We have been contacted
by the tracking unit.
里から およそ半日の地点で
カンクロウを発見
Kankuro was discovered about
half a day out of the village.
意識不明の重体だそうです
He is unconscious and
in serious condition.
（バキ）あ…
Kankuro...
（バキ）カンクロウ
Some members of the tracking unit
have recovered Kankuro and his puppets.
（砂の里の忍）追跡部隊の一部が
カンクロウと傀儡くぐつ人形を回収
里に向かっているとのこと
They are on their way
back to the village.
What about the location
of Lord Kazekage?
（バキ）風影様の行方は？
The remaining members of
the tracking unit are in pursuit.
（砂の里の忍）
残りの者が追っております
まもなく報告が入るかと…
There should be a report soon...
（デイダラ）遅いぞ
サソリの旦那 うん
You're late, Sasori my man...
I thought you didn't like to
keep people waiting.
人を待たせるのは
嫌いじゃなかったのか？
（サソリ）だが その分
たっぷり楽しめた
But...I had enough fun
to make up for that.
What's up with that?
（デイダラ）なんだい そりゃ
（サソリ）まあ
そうカリカリすんな
Don't get so touchy.
You secured your mission target,
the One-Tail, after all.
お前のノルマ１尾は
確保したんだからよう
こいつの処理が終わったら
次は俺のノルマだな
My mission comes next...
after taking care of this guy.
（デイダラ）けど
サソリの旦那の相手って…
But the one you're after...
Yeah, I still don't know where he is...
（サソリ）ああ まだどこに
いるかも分かりゃしねえ
向こうから来てくれりゃあ
楽なんだがな
It'd be easier if
he'd just come to me...
（デイダラ）ああ そうだな
Yeah...That's right...
What kind of Jinchuriki
was he again?
どんな人柱力じんちゅうりきだったっけ？
（サソリ）まあ最悪
そいつを見つけられなくても
Well, worst case scenario,
even if I can't find him...
（サソリ）人柱力 １匹
捕まえりゃ文句ねえだろ
nobody can complain
since we caught one of the Jinchuriki.
（うずまきナルト）我愛羅
今 行くってばよ
Gaara, we're coming...!
（春野はるのサクラ）
ナルト いくら急いでるからって
隊は乱しちゃダメ
Naruto! I know you're in a hurry,
but don't disrupt the unit!
But, but...!
（ナルト）でもさ でもさ…
Don't lose your cool...
（はたけカカシ）そう熱くなるな
Master Jiraiya told you not to,
remember?
自来也じらいや様にも そう言われたんだろ
（ナルト）な… ああっ
For crying out loud...
（サクラ）ったく もう…
あっ
テマリさん
Temari!
（テマリ）ん？
Hurry up and get him
to the operating room!
（砂の里の忍）急いで手術室へ
Operating Room
Is this...poison?!
これは… 毒か？
Prepare an antidote!
解毒薬の用意を
（カンクロウ）我愛羅… 我愛羅…
Gaara...
What?! Gaara was...?!
（テマリ）何 我愛羅が！
I was having a bad feeling...
（テマリ）嫌な予感はしてたんだ
It'll take about two and a half days
to get to the Sand from here...
（カカシ）ここから砂まで
２日半はかかるからな
Let's hurry.
（カカシ）急ごう
（テマリ）ああ
Right.
Treatment Room 3
（砂の里の忍）ケガのほうは
たいしたこと ありませんでした
The wounds weren't that serious...
問題は…
The problem is...
（バキ）毒… か
（砂の里の忍）はい
The poison, huh...?
Yes, it's a completely new poison.
まったくの新しい毒です
解毒方法の見当がまるでつきません
We have absolutely no idea
how to neutralize it.
Gaara...and now Kankuro, too...
我愛羅…
そしてカンクロウまで
（カンクロウ）う… うう
（サクラ）あっ
Taking Naruto is the top-priority duty
（うちはイタチ）
ナルト君を連れて行くのが
わが組織 暁あかつきから下された
我々への至上命令だ
given to us by our organization,
the Akatsuki.
（自来也）ヤツらが狙ってるのは
お前というより お前の中のものだ
It's not so much you
that they're after...
it's what's inside you they want.
But as long as you have
the Nine-Tails sealed within you...
（自来也）ただ お前に九尾が
封印されている以上
they might want to have that power
under their own control...
ヤツらは その力を
自分たちの支配下におきたいと
考えているのかもしれない
Naruto! I told you earlier
not to disrupt the unit...
（サクラ）ナルト
さっきも言ったでしょ
隊を乱しちゃダメだって
（ナルト）
気にくわねえんだってばよ
I don't like it!
（サクラ）ああ
（テマリ）あ…
（ナルト）あいつらが俺や我愛羅を
狙う理由ぐらい俺にだって分かる
Even I know why they're after
people like Gaara and me...
サクラちゃんも
もう知ってんだろ？
You know it already,
don't you, Sakura...?
That I've got...
（ナルト）俺の中に…
俺の中に九尾きゅうびの妖狐ようこが
封印されてんの
...the Nine-Tailed Fox Spirit
sealed inside me...
（テマリ）はっ！
（女性）ほら あれ例の子よ
Hey, it's that kid.
Eww, let's get out of here.
（女性）ヤダヤダ
あっち行きましょう
Gaara and I both...
have monsters inside us...
（ナルト）我愛羅も俺も
俺たちは化け物を
体の中に飼ってっからな
それが目当てなんだ あいつらは
That's what they're after!
それが気にくわねえ
That's what I don't like!
They only see us as monsters!
俺たちを化け物としか見てねえ
あいつらの好き勝手な見方が
気にくわねえんだ
I don't like their selfish way
of viewing us!
（我愛羅）化け物か…
A monster, huh...?
それならば俺もそうだ
If that's the case,
then we're the same...
俺は生まれながらの化け物だ
That's right. I was born a monster.
（ナルト）あいつは
俺と全部 同じだった
Everything about us...
was the same...
（テマリ）あ…
And he...fought all by himself
a lot more than me...
（ナルト）そして あいつは
俺よりも独りぼっちで
ずっと戦ってたんだ
Naruto...
（サクラ）ナルト…
To them, I'm now an artifact
of a past they want to erase.
（我愛羅）ヤツらにとって
今では消し去りたい過去の異物だ
Then why should I exist
and what should I live for?
では俺は なんのために
存在し生き続けてるのか
そう考えたとき
答えは見つからなかった
I thought about it,
but couldn't find an answer...
だが生きてる間は
その理由が必要なのだ
But I need that reason while I'm alive...
If not, it's the same as dying...
でなければ死んでいるのと同じだ
（ナルト）暁に狙われてた
The Akatsuki was after him!
今度も俺と同じだ
It's just like me this time, too...
それなのに なんで
いつも あいつばっかりが
And yet, why does he always
have to be
the one to get the short end
of the stick?!
損な役回りになっちまう
あいつばっかりが…
It's always him!
That's why I can't be wasting
any time getting to him!
だから…
だから どうしたって
ちんたらしてらんねえだろ
This time, I want to save him
right away!
今度こそ さっさと助けてえんだ
Naruto...
（テマリ）うずまきナルト
Uzumaki...
Thank you...
ありがと
You say Kankuro's regained
consciousness?
（バキ）カンクロウの
意識が戻っただと？
あ… 戻ったといっても
He has, but he's just barely
able to respond to us...
なんとか こちらの言葉に
反応するといった程度で
His condition has worsened
since yesterday.
状態は きのうより悪化してます
ん…
うう… バキ
Baki... Is that you...?
いるのか？
Kankuro!
（バキ）カンクロウ
It's...it's him...
あいつだ… うう！
大きな声を出すな
体に障る ん？
Don't raise your voice!
It's not good for you
in your condition!
Th-Th Red Sand...
（カンクロウ）あ… 赤砂あかすなの…
（バキ）あっ！
そうか そういうことだったのか
I see... So that explains it...
Lord Baki...?
バキ様
う… ううっ
（砂の里の忍）あっ バキ様
Oh, Lord Baki.
（バキ）追跡部隊に連絡しろ
すぐに引き返させるんだ
Contact the tracking unit!
Tell them to turn back immediately!
あ… それが きのうカンクロウを
回収して以降 連絡が途絶えていて
Actually, we haven't heard
anything from them
since recovering Kankuro yesterday...
We were too late...
遅かったか
We have no choice
but to consult with them...
あの方たちに相談するしかないな
（砂の里の忍）あっ なんです？
Huh? What is it?
Nothing...
I'm...going out for a bit.
（バキ）いや 少し出かけてくる
Oh, but...!
（砂の里の忍）あ… しかし
Our superiors told us to give them
a progress report this morning...
きょうの午前中には
経過報告をと 上のほうから…
Do you think I have the time
to be leisurely giving reports?!
のんびり報告など
している暇があると思うか
Action takes precedence
over meetings right now!
今は会議より行動が優先だ
Y-Yes, sir!
あ… はい
This is what happens
as soon as Gaara disappears...
（バキ）
我愛羅がいなくなった途端に
これか まったく
Give me a break...
I have no choice but to consult
with the honorable siblings...
あの ご姉弟きょうだいに
相談するしかあるまい
But I wonder...
will they come to our aid willingly?
だが素直に
出てきてくださるかどうか…
Now, now, the food pills are
only for emergencies...
（カカシ）はいはい 兵糧丸ひょうろうがんは
あくまでも非常食だからね
Girls of your age especially need
to be careful not to eat too...
（カカシ）特に お年頃の
女の子は食べ過ぎ注…
She got mad...
（カカシ）怒っちゃった
That's totally sexual harassment...
old man.
（テマリ）そりゃ立派な
セクハラだぞ オヤジ
Naruto.
（サクラ）ナルト
（ナルト）あ？
You've met him before, haven't you?
（サクラ）あんた
会ったことあるんでしょ？
（ナルト）は？
（サクラ）うちはイタチに
Itachi Uchiha...
And he's after you.
そして彼に狙われている
I didn't just train over these past
two and a half years.
私も この２年半ただ修行だけ
してたわけじゃないわ
I got into Master Tsunade's library
綱手つなで師匠の書斎に勝手に入り込んだり
外に出て調べられるだけ調べた
and did outside investigations
the best I could.
そして 今まで引っかかってたことが
ようやく１つにつながった
And now... what was bothering me
finally makes sense now!
I wouldn't call it a dream,
but I've got an ambition!
（うちはサスケ）夢なんて言葉で
終わらす気はないが野望はある
一族の復興と
ある男を必ず殺すことだ
To restore the clan and
to kill a certain man...no matter what!
I'm the only one who can kill him.
俺にしか あの男は殺せない
I'm an avenger.
俺は復しゅう者だ
あの男より強くならなきゃならねえ
I have to become stronger
than him...
I don't have time to be getting
tripped up in a place like this.
こんなところで
つまづいている暇はない
The person Sasuke wants to kill...
（サクラ）
サスケ君が殺したい相手って
実の兄 うちはイタチのことでしょ
is his own older brother
Itachi Uchiha, right...?
A member of the Akatsuki!
暁の一員の
Itachi...Uchiha!
（サスケ）うちはイタチ
Itachi...Uchiha?
うちはイタチ
（サスケ）あんたを殺す
I'm going to kill you!
（サスケ）あんたの言ったとおり
あんたを恨み憎み そして
Just as you told me to do,
I've resented you, hated you, and...
あんたを殺すためだけに俺は…
I've lived...
俺は生きてきた！
only to kill you!
Sure enough, you're brothers...
（大蛇丸おろちまる）やっぱり兄弟だわね
I see power greater than Itachi's hidden
in those eyes of yours...
あのイタチ以上の
能力を秘めた目をしている
Sasuke will definitely seek me out...
サスケ君は必ず私を求める
in search of power...
力を求めてね
That's why Sasuke is with Orochimaru
in an attempt to obtain power...
だからサスケ君は今
大蛇丸のところで
力を手に入れようとしている
But Orochimaru is
after Sasuke's body, right?
けど大蛇丸は
サスケ君の体が目的なんでしょ
And we only have six months left!
しかも あと半年しか時間がない
（ナルト）サクラちゃんも
そのことを…
Sakura knows about that too...
（サクラ）そして その大蛇丸は
元暁のメンバーの１人だった
And Orochimaru used to be
a member of the Akatsuki.
Basically this is what I want...to say.
つまり私が言いたいのは
こういうことよ
The closer we get to the Akatsuki,
暁に近づけば近づくほど
大蛇丸の情報にも近づける
the closer we get to information
about Orochimaru...
そうなれば おのずと
サスケ君にも近づける
If that happens...
we'll eventually get closer to Sasuke!
うん
And after that, Itachi Uchiha...
（サクラ）それに
そのあとは うちはイタチ
Our worst enemy who
plagued Sasuke for so long...
サスケ君をずっと苦しめ
ナルトを狙う最悪の敵
and the one who's after Naruto...
This time I'll  save the two of them!
今度は２人を私が助ける
（エビゾウ）あっ
誰か来たようだな
It appears someone's come...
Say, Big Sister...
姉ちゃんよう
Hey, Big Sister...!
おい 姉ちゃんよう
わあ！
死んだか？
うお
（チヨ）なんてな
死んだフリ
アッハハハ…
そういうリアルな
ボケするない 姉ちゃん
ん？
（バキ）ご姉弟
お二人に お力を
お貸しいただきたく参りました
（チヨ）古書物は束ねて高い棚に
載せたままにしておくもんでのう
いまさら わしらに何ができる
暁という組織が刺客を…
このまま放っておけば
大変なことに…
（エビゾウ）お前たちの時代だ
己らで なんとかしろよ
（バキ）あなた方は各国に
協力なパイプを持っておられる
同盟国ではない国の里にも
独自のルートを
私たちだけで情報を
かき集めるには限界が
（チヨ）はあ
わしらは とうに隠居の身じゃ
いまさら世俗に
なんの未練もないわい
あるとすりゃあ もう一度
孫の顔を拝みたいくらいでの
（バキ）それは好都合
（エビゾウ･チヨ）は？
（バキ）暁のメンバーの１人に
お孫さんがいらっしゃいます
チヨバア様
♪～
～♪
桜の花咲くこの季節
年に１度の大チャンス
ことしも やります当たります
木ノ葉じゃん ジャンボ宝くじ
１等賞金２千万両
買えばリッチな倍チャンス
買わないあなたは大ショック
のるかそるかと言われれば
のって極楽 一直線
夢のバラ色 人生の
チケットたったの30両
賭けてみないと このチャンス
賭けてみようぜ このチャンス
木ノ葉じゃん ジャンボ宝くじ
明朝10時
発売開始
セレブな生活をあなたの手に
よっしゃあ 買った
次回「封印術
･幻龍げんりゅう九封尽きゅうふうじん」
（サクラ）巻物によって
契約した生き物を自在に呼び出す
時空間忍術 口寄くちよせの術
ナルト 今までどんな
口寄せ動物たちが
登場したか覚えてる？
（ナルト）えっと
ガマオヤビンだろ 綱手つなでばあちゃんの
カツユに大蛇丸のマンダ
カカシ先生のパックンたち
（サクラ）ほかにも
テマリさんのカマタリ
３代目火影ほかげ様の猿魔えんま
変わったところで音忍おとにん 多由也たゆやのドキ
右近うこん 左近さこんのラショウモン
なんてのもあったわね
（ナルト）ああ
そういやあガイ先生
ニンガメの口寄せ
できたんだっけなあ？
まあ 使ってるとこ
１回っきゃ見たことねえけど
（サクラ）でも
こういう動物たちって
ふだん どんなところに
いるのかしら？
（ナルト）おうおう そういうのは
本人に聞くのがいちばん
（サクラ）え！ ちょっと まさか
（ナルト）任せてくれってばよ
いでよ ガマオヤビン
（ナルト･サクラ）だあ！